The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Forbidden Area\NSoul Refining Sect
Little friend Ceng Niu,
you're finally back.
This place
is the Soul Refining Sect's forbidden area.
Only those who have mastered Soul Sealing
can enter it.
Death aura...
He's at the end of his lifespan...
Senior...you...
It's alright.
I still have a few years left.
I won’t die too soon.
I must thank Senior
regarding the Soul Flag.
It's fine as long as it helped you.
In these short years,
your cultivation level has increased a lot.
You're already at the point where you need to absorb
celestial spiritual energy to refine your body.
This old man
can lend you a hand with that.
But this help
comes with a price.
Senior, please speak.
These tablets are from all the past Soul Transformation cultivators of the sect.
I entrust the Soul Refining Sect to you
in front of all the ancestors.
And what I ask of you in return
is that you protect the Billion-Soul Flag.
As long as it exists,
the Soul Refining Sect will live.
This planet is too small
to hold someone like you, Ceng Niu.
When you leave this place one day,
you must find a place suitable
for our Soul Refining Sect.
You must also build 999 heaven-reaching towers
to fulfill our sect's dream
by making us
a rank 6 cultivation country !
I accept.
Senior Brother,
I have gambled everything on your divination.
I hope that
this gamble will pay off in the end.
Our reserves of celestial jades
aren't enough for your Soul Transformation.
I'll take you to gather more celestial jades.
Are there other places
besides the Celestial Realm ?
Friends will help us.
Demonic Insect Sect
Mice of the Demonic Insect Sect,
your grandfather Du Tian has come !
Quickly hand over the celestial jades !
Yan Hong\NDemonic Insect Sect Ancestor\NEarly stage Soul Transformation
Cha Zi\NDemonic Insect Sect Ancestor\NEarly stage Soul Transformation
Old ghost Du Tian,
there are no more celestial jades !
Really ?
Give me the celestial jades
and I'll leave.
If you don't,
I won't fight you,
but I'll kill all the insects of this swamp.
I'll exterminate them all !
The Soul Refining Sect are all crazy.
When their lifespan is almost up,
they fearlessly
use this Soul Flag
to steal celestial jades...
Old ghost,
if you dare attack,
the Junior beside you
will die for sure !
Do you
still think I will die today ?
How can a Soul Formation cultivator have a celestial artifact ?
Who the hell are you !?
I am
Ceng Niu.
He's the one that killed Li Yuanfeng and the Giant Demon Ancestor
while at Soul Formation, Ceng Niu !
Enough talk.
Same rules,
give me half of your celestial jades.
Take them
and don't ever come back !
See ?
I told you friends would help us.
Last time, my master stole a lot from them
yet they still have this many left !
However...
It's still not enough.
It doesn't matter.
If one isn't enough, rob two.
If two aren't enough, rob three !
With the Billion-Soul Flag in hand,
we can go all around the planet.
Let's go,
next target !
The Soul Refining Sect
really is something.
Alright,
these celestial jades should suffice.
If you need more later,
you must steal them yourself.
Little friend Ceng Niu,
remember this.
In the cultivation world,
the best way to get celestial jades is to steal them.
In the future,
you must take the Billion-Soul Flag and do the same.
Don't tarnish our Soul Refining Sect's reputation !
Okay.
But either you steal everything
or you steal nothing !
Good, good, good.
But planet Suzaku is too small.
In my youth,
I once visited Planet Tian Yun.
It's 10 times larger than planet Suzaku,
has many sects
and abundant resources.
If not for my lack of strength,
I'd have plundered it !
It would've been thrilling.
Planet Tian Yun...
The All-Seer lives on planet Tian Yun.
His cultivation is unfathomable
He is rumored to hold a position
in the Cultivation Alliance.
He is far beyond our insignificant Zhuque Zi.
I am the All-Seer.
If you can leave this waste of a planet,
then come find me on planet Tian Yun
to become my honorary disciple
and follow me for 100 years.
Once I have settled things on planet Suzaku,
I must go to Planet Tian Yun.
It's the Forsaken Immortal Clan,
they're heading for the Suzaku Continent.
I didn't expect a second attack so soon.
Let's not get involved
and quickly return to the sect.
The Soul Refining Sect...
Mu Ye,
go meet up with Junior Patriarch,
I'll catch up with you.
Understood.
You two from the Soul Refining Sect,
Cui Zhi\NFifth Ancestor of the\NForsaken Immortal Clan \N9-Leaf Shaman
hand over your artifacts.
A 9-Leaf Shaman...
I heard that in the great war thousands of years ago,
your Soul Refining Sect dominated the battlefield with the Billion-Soul Flag.
Let me see
if the power of this artifact
is real
or not !
You aren't worthy of the Billion Soul Flag.
However...
Little friend Ceng Niu,
the sects we robbed before
were just small fry.
Take this chance
to witness the true power
of the Billion-Soul Flag.
Watch closely !
500 million souls,
13 primary souls,
come out !
Remember,
the essence
of the Billion-Soul Flag's power
is merging.
There is no fixed method of using it.
Formation,
activate !
The 6th generation ancestor excelled in formations.
In his hands, this flag
became an a tool for formations.
Thirteen Souls Formation...
Soul Refining !
This formation can extract souls ?
Interesting.
Break !
Glass Cauldrons !
Refine !
A 9-Leaf Shaman
is equivalent to Early stage Ascendant.
He has some skill
Is this all
the Billion-Soul Flag can do ?
Do you know why the Billion-Soul Flag
is feared even by Ascendants ?
I will show it to you today !
The 10th ancestor's domain was devouring.
In his hands,
the flag devoured souls
to make him stronger.
500 million souls
and 13 primary souls merged together.
Senior Du Tian's cultivation
has reached
Middle stage Ascendant !
Scram !
This old man won't kill you today.
But you must remember
that our Soul Refining Sect won't participate
in your war
with Suzaku.
Thank you Senior for sparing me.
I'll inform our clan.
This is the power of our Billion-Soul Flag.
What do you think ?
Thank you Senior for your guidance.
When my lifespan ends,
you will wield this flag
and explore its possibilities even further.
Senior Du Tian and I
aren't master and disciple.
But he still taught me the flag's secrets,
so he's my teacher now.
Kid, you're quite lucky.
I can sense
that the fourth primary soul is awakening.
The fourth primary soul ?
Yes.
It's the strongest among the 36 primary souls
and our Soul Refining Sect's
last Ascendant Ancestor.
Ascendant...
How did he fall ?
This matter
begins with the second Suzaku
Back then,
when Suzaku defeated the Forsaken Immortal Clan,
the first Suzaku sacrificed himself
to seal the Forsaken Immortal Clan
under the surface.
He appointed someone
as the second Suzaku.
He was a man of great talent
and the undisputed
strongest person on Suzaku.
I really am lucky.
I, Situ Nan,
the strongest person
on planet Suzaku,
will take your body !
Senior,
what was the second Suzaku's name ?
I don't know.
His name
must only be known by its successors.
During his reign,
planet Suzaku flourished.
Our sect's fourth ancestor
reached Ascendant
during that time.
What became of him ?
Thousands of years ago,
4 foreign cultivators invaded Suzaku.
The fourth ancestor fought alongside the second Suzaku.
Even if he won his duel,
the fourth ancestor was badly wounded
and became the fourth primary soul.
And the second Suzaku
disappeared.
A mortal...
I waited thousands of years
just to get a mere mortal !
I can't even possess you !
According to Senior Du Tian,
this second Suzaku
sounds a lot like Situ Nan.
Is it really him ?
That's enough,
it's all in the past anyways.
The Suzaku Continent is ahead.
What matters now,
is that we return to the Soul Refining Sect
for your Soul Transformation.
This formation's size
is astonishing.
Planet Suzaku's strongest formation,
the Suzaku Formation.
When deployed
it can envelop the entire planet
or shrink to protect a single person.
It's incredibly powerful.
The amount of spirit stones needed to activate it
is unimaginable.
Zhuque Zi is sparing no expense in this war with
the Forsaken Immortal Clan.
This formation contains
Giant Demon blood !?
I remember now.
That Qian Feng kid
visited the Giant Demon Clan.
He broke your seal on their cultivation
and moved them to Suzaku.
I wondered why they were so generous
but they were after their blood
to strengthen the formation.
Qian Feng broke the seal
without me noticing ?
He's not to be underestimated...
Zhuque Zi,
open this formation for me !
Or I will risk my life
to blast open a gap
before the Forsaken Immortla Clan even arrives !
My patience is limited.
Three...
Two...
Senior, don't get angry.
Junior will open it.
The Suzaku Formation
is only taught to Suzaku successors.
Since Zhuque Zi taught you early,
he must have high hopes for you.
You flatter me, Senior.
Junior means no harm.
I merely wish to spar
with the famous Ceng Niu,
that's all.
Enough.
I don't have time to waste with you.
Could it be
that Senior's successor
lacks the courage to face me ?
Kid,
you're courting death !
Alright,
I'll fight you.
After Du Tian told the story of the fourth ancestor and the second Suzaku fighting foreign cultivators, Wang Lin asks if he knows if any of these cultivators were by any chance named "Na Duo" (Wang Lin met Na Duo in episode 53).\N\N“That’s right, the ancestor recorded one of the names of the four foreign cultivators. That person said that he was from planet Five Elements and was called Na Duo. Yes, that should be correct. Once we go back, I’ll give you the jade with the records.”\N\N-> I think that the person that dueled the fourth ancestor was Na Duo. He was surprised by the Billion-Soul Flag combined with the fourth ancestor's Ascendant cultivation and was severly injured. That explains why he got hurt so badly and took thousands of years to recover 30% of his cultivation as a corpse in the War God Shrine.\N\NEven if this is the most likely scenario, it's also weird that someone as strong as Na Duo (whose cultivation at 100% is way past Ascendant) would lose to someone as weak as the fourth ancestor. Maybe he wasn't at 100% when he attacked planet Suzaku. Maybe I'm missing something. Maybe it's a plot hole.
To let go of the consequences of my actions
is to ignore the law of cause and effect
like scattered ink.
As destiny falls
in exchange for this moment of tainted dreams.
It makes the mountains lose their colors,
wither and melt into rivers.
Who can deceive
the law of the heavens ?
Countless generations
have tried before me.
But how could I not catch my dreams
within my warm fingers ?
You're at my side when I'm alone
giving me the strength to fight the will of the heavens.
Fortunately, my mind was open and honest.
I'm sorry we never got to see the fireworks
in the streets.
Can I break the vortex of our destiny ?
Can I break the rules ?
To run towards you !
I will fight the law of the heavens and the law of cause and effect
to cut down this tribulation with my own hands
and break through the reincarnation cycle.
All of that for the stars in your eyes.
I wish to bend this dream for the fire in my heart.
If your soul is willing to wander,
can I still take your hands
and hold them tight ?
I will defy the heavens and prevent the stars from falling.
I will overthrow the Immortals and the Demons in my heart.
I dream of destroying
the shackles of our fate.
You're the only one that can ignore the law of cause and effect.
You're the hardest to let go of.
I want to be with you again
so I can look in your eyes.
Even for a moment, it's worth it.